Wilcox College of Nursing Records
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Wilcox College of Nursing Records
undated, 1907-2007.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
75.25 linear feet.
MSS19980018
The Middlesex Memorial Hospital was founded in 1904 and given authority to operate a school of nursing in 1908. The first class of three students graduated 20 February 1910. The school was approved by the State Board of Examiners in 1918, and first granted accreditation by the National League for Nursing in 1946. In 1970, in honor of a graduate and 45 year employee, the school changed its name to Ona M. Wilcox School of Nursing, and again when it was granted accreditation by the state as a college, to Wilcox College of Nursing. In 1997, after years of debate, the college closed due to insufficient funding and lack of support. Information regarding student enrollment and course work (transcripts) has been retained by the Department of Education, Middlesex Hospital (860.344.6480).
History
The Ona M. Wilcox College of Nursing was first established in 1908 under the direction and supervision of Middlesex Hospital. It was known as the Middlesex Hospital Training School and, although a private institution funded by the hospital, was not for profit.
Admission into the two year, three month program was based upon vacancy. Women had to be between the ages of twenty-one and thirty-five, and unmarried or widowed. The application packet consisted of an information sheet requiring the applicant's height, weight, and religion, among other questions. The applicant also needed to submit a personal letter, a physician's statement on her health, and a letter from her pastor upholding her moral character. Once admitted, students were required to purchase the standard material and sew their own uniforms (although not their nursing outfit).
Student nurses first began a probationary period of two months. If she completed the period satisfactorily and chose to stay, she was required to sign an agreement stating she would complete the rest of her training and would faithfully obey the rules of the school. At this time she was given her nursing outfit and her “cap” during the Capping ceremony.
Student turnover was high during the early years. Students could be discharged based upon misconduct, inefficiency or neglect of duty, but more frequently students left to be married or due to personal or family illness. Illness was quite frequent and in 1913 student nurses were required to be vaccinated for small pox and typhoid fever.
Students were expected to obey strict rules including curfew, roll call, visiting hours and studying hours. The official day began at 7:00 am. and duties continued until 7:00 p.m., with a few hours off weekly for church and courting. Men were not allowed in the living areas, which, until the construction of Hendley Memorial Hall in 1913, was the top floor of the hospital. A two week vacation was allotted each year, but personal illness beyond those two weeks had to be made up. Rules governing the nurses appearance were also strict. It was not until a board vote in May 1925, that students were allowed to wear bobbed hair, and not until January 1931, that students were allowed to smoke (although not in their rooms).
Although most of their course work and training was done within the Middlesex Hospital, student nurses completed three months of training at the affiliated New York Hospital. Later affiliations were made elsewhere such as in Hartford and with neighboring Weslyan University.
In 1909, the program was extended to two and a half years, and again in 1914, to three years. The first class of three students graduated 20 February 1910. But class size steadily grew due to demand for nurses during World War I, and later during World War II. At many points the demand exceeded the supply, so much so that the Governor of Connecticut almost signed a bill establishing a nursing draft.
The first male student, Anthony Sebastian Nucifora, graduated in 1974. Although males continued to be a part of the school thereafter, their numbers remained in the minority. Records show that the first minority woman of color, Beatrice Byrd graduated in 1955. Agendas at many meetings helped to form an open and encouraging policy towards minority students of race and ethnicity, but still did not bring in significant numbers.
In 1932, the Middlesex Hospital Training School became the Middlesex Hospital School of Nursing, and nine years later became one of three schools in Connecticut and seventy-three in the United States to be accredited by the National League for Nursing. Before full accreditation was given in 1958, the school changed names again to the Middlesex Memorial Hospital School of Nursing.
Many of Wilcox's nursing students stayed on to work in the Hospital after graduation. Ona M. Wilcox was only one of them. Graduating in 1925, Miss Wilcox spent almost all of her working life dedicated to her school, first as Night Supervisor, then as Obstetrical Supervisor, then as the Assistant Director of Nursing. Upon completion of her Bachelors degree from Columbia University and a Masters from New York University, Miss Wilcox was named Director of the school in 1943. After her retirement in 1970, the school board voted unanimously to change its name to the Ona M. Wilcox School of Nursing.
In the 1970s and 1980s, the school began using funding from outside resources to make improvements to the school's library, classrooms, and living areas. The Helen Fuld Trust Fund became the principle means of acquiring such monies for updating and modernizing the school. Although the cost of attending the school was comparable to other private institutions, the class size was far less. The Ona M. Wilcox School of Nursing was not for profit and depended more and more upon the funding from Middlesex Hospital. In 1992, in hopes of expanding, the School earned full accreditation by the state of Connecticut as a Nursing College and changed the name for the last time to the Ona M. Wilcox College of Nursing. The student nurses completed many Liberal Arts requirements under an affiliation agreement with Middlesex Community College, while plans for further expanding the program were being developed. Lack of space became a key issue and inquiries were made into purchasing a neighboring office building, dependent upon the possibility of State assistance.
In 1994, when it became clear that funding would not be allocated for such purposes, the board of directors voted to close the college. Although protests were heard by residents, alumni, and employees, the Middlesex Hospital felt that the cost of operating the college outweighed the benefits.
In 1997, after the last class of 68 (day and evening) students completed the program, the Wilcox College of Nursing closed its doors forever.
Scope and Content
The Wilcox College of Nursing collection contains photographs, slides, memorabilia (including a nursing doll), nursing uniforms, videos, scrapbooks, editorials, administrative records, financial records and correspondence. Almost all personnel and student files were retained by the Middlesex Hospital and will be destroyed after the year 2000.
Class photographs are not available for the following years: 1911, 1917-1919, 1941, 1966.
Arrangement
The collection has been arranged by content, and then by date. Files were maintained chronologically and alphabetically therein. This filing system is reflected in the finding aid.
Series I: Infrastructure & Finances ( undated, 1948-1997 )
Series II: Personnel, Students & Curriculum ( undated, 1907-1997 )
Series III: Administration ( undated, 1909-1997 )
Series IV: Press Materials and Photographs ( undated, 1909-1997 )
Series V: Memorabilia ( undated, 1947-2007 )
Series VI: Audiovisual materials ( 1993-1996 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to nursing in Connecticut. See especially, the Josephine Dolan Collection of Nursing History, Virginia Henderson Research Collection, Connecticut Training School for Nurses Alumni Association Records, and the North East Organization for Nursing Records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Celebration of Nursing 1998-0018.vr1
Bibliography
All material described within the Institution History section has been based upon the Wilcox Collection. Administrative records, committee meeting minutes, student handbooks, editorials and correspondence were all used in the construction of this document.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Wilcox College of Nursing.; Middlesex Hospital (Conn.).; Nursing—History—Connecticut.; Nursing schools—History—Connecticut—Middletown.; Nursing—Study and teaching—History—Connecticut.; Middletown (Conn.)—History.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Notebooks.; Publications.; Photographs.; Blueprints.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; School Records.; Uniforms.; Dolls.; Videocassettes.
Restrictions on Access
The following folders are restricted: 623, 611-618, 567-568. These folders have been separated from the collection and are restricted due to the contents of the folder. Please contact the collection curator for more information.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated to the University of Connecticut in April 1998 by the Wilcox College of Nursing.
Two nursing pins (Middlesex Memorial Hospital School of Nursing) were donated in 2006 by Joan Burns (Class of 1960).
Detailed Description
- Series I: Infrastructure & Finances, undated, 1948-1997
  - Building Renovations through Helen Fuld Trust Grant
    - Learning Center proposal—correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - Science Laboratory proposal—correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Science Laboratory architectural plans, 1978-1979 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - Redecorating of Bengston-Wood Hall living room proposal—correspondence, 1980 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Computer Center / Library proposal—correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Student Bathrooms proposal—correspondence, 1983 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Student Bathrooms—correspondence (by date), 1984 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Student Lounge proposal—correspondence, 1988 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Relocation Plans
    - Newfield Building purchasing and renovation plans, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 9)
    - Equipment planning for Fields Building, 1993-1994 (Box 2:, Folder 10)
    - Reorganization of college space - notes, 1992-1993 (Box 2:, Folder 11)
    - Wilcox College Relocation
      - Meeting minutes, 1993 (Box 2:, Folder 12)
      - Charney Architects plan, 1992-1993 (Box 3:, Folder 13)
      - Notes, correspondence, 1993 (Box 3:, Folder 14)
      - Applications for C.O.N., 1993 (Box 3:, Folder 15)
      - Certificate of Need drafts, final, 1993 (Box 3:, Folder 16)
      - Planning and Zoning for Newfield Building, 1993 (Box 3:, Folder 17)
      - Floor plans and budget, 1993 (Box 3:, Folder 18)
      - Construction Bidders, 1993 (Box 3:, Folder 19)
      - Moving plan & fundraiser information, 1993 (Box 3:, Folder 20)
      - Food services, 1993 (Box 3:, Folder 21)
      - Equipment needs, 1994 (Box 3:, Folder 22)
      - Charney Architects plan for re-organization of space, 1994 (Box 3:, Folder 23)
  - Federal Aid / Grants
    - Federal Aid - Title VI Application, undated (Box 4:, Folder 24)
    - Nurse Training Act of 1964 related material, 1966-1967 (Box 4:, Folder 25)
    - Nursing grants booklets and applications, undated (Box 4:, Folder 26)
    - Nursing Capitation Grant
      - Applications, proposals, correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 4:, Folder 27)
      - Applications, proposals, correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 4:, Folder 28)
      - Applications, proposals, correspondence, 1977-1984 (Box 4:, Folder 29)
    - Helen Fuld Trust Grant
      - Correspondence, financial records, 1985-1987 (Box 4:, Folder 30)
      - Application and contract, 1985 (Box 4:, Folder 31)
      - Application, 1983 (Box 4:, Folder 32)
  - Finances
    - Finances, undated (Box 5:, Folder 33)
    - School fees and Tuition costs, 1966 (Box 5:, Folder 34)
    - IRS -completed forms, notes, correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 5:, Folder 35)
    - Taxes, 1948 (Box 5:, Folder 36)
    - Cost Analysis for Connecticut Hospital Association, 1949-1959 (Box 5:, Folder 37)
    - Cost Analysis for Connecticut Hospital Association, 1960-1970 (Box 5:, Folder 38)
  - Historical / Transformation to College
    - Historical Notes, undated (Box 6:, Folder 39)
    - Report to Association of Diploma Schools of Nursing in Connecticut by Richard Steele Consultants, 1979 March (Box 6:, Folder 40)
    - Transition Model Syllabus, 1984-1985 (Box 6:, Folder 41)
    - Nursing Ed. Task Force - Birch & Davis Report, 1988 (Box 6:, Folder 42)
    - Nursing Ed. Task Force - Birch & Davis Report w/ notes, 1988 (Box 6:, Folder 43)
    - Transformation to college report, 1991 (Box 6:, Folder 44)
    - Transformation to college report from the Bristol Group, 1992 (Box 6:, Folder 45)
    - Federal Program participation renewal forms, 1991 (Box 6:, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence about transformation, 1992 (Box 6:, Folder 47)
    - Program change to 2 year program report, 1990 (Box 6:, Folder 48)
    - College Charter, correspondence relating to & speeches, 1993 (Box 6:, Folder 49)
    - By-Laws and certificate of incorporation, 1991 (Box 6:, Folder 50)
  - Closure
    - Computer disk- Bristol Group presentation (prob. Mac), circa 1996 (Box 7:, Folder 51)
    - Closure report, 1995 September (Box 7:, Folder 52)
    - Correspondence, memoranda and notes, 1992-1993 (Box 7:, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence, memoranda and notes, 1994 (Box 7:, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence, memoranda and notes, 1995-1996 (Box 7:, Folder 55)
    - Vision, goals and action plan, 1995-1997 (Box 7:, Folder 56)
- Series II: Personnel, Students & Curriculum, undated, 1907-1997
  - Admissions, Progress Reports
    - Admissions and student record book, 1907-1913 (Box 8:, Folder 57)
    - Training records, evaluations, 1916-1918 (Box 8:, Folder 58)
    - Ona Wilcox Application, letter of interest, recommendations, health record, dentist's certificate, 1922 (Box 8:, Folder 59)
    - Ona Wilcox plaque and painting related materials, 1971-1973 (Box 8:, Folder 60)
    - Rachel Alice Symington's footprints- left and right, 1924 (Box 8:, Folder 61)
    - Gladys Johnson - (2) x-rays, 1926 (Box 8:, Folder 62)
    - Katherine Scoboria photograph and application, 1938 (Box 8:, Folder 63)
    - Barbara Roser photograph and application, 1939 (Box 8:, Folder 64)
    - Lucy Costanzo photograph and application, 1939 (Box 8:, Folder 65)
    - Claire Cornwall photograph and application, 1939 (Box 8:, Folder 66)
    - Alice Nelson photograph and application, 1939 (Box 8:, Folder 67)
    - Mildred Blaschke photograph and application, 1939 (Box 8:, Folder 68)
    - Elizabeth Marie Cofrancesco photograph and application, 1939 (Box 8:, Folder 69)
    - Evelyn Lucille Anne Bennett application, interview sheet, reference sheet and photograph, 1939 (Box 8:, Folder 70)
    - Catherine Flynn photograph and application, 1939 (Box 8:, Folder 71)
    - Anastasia Chaponis photograph and application, 1940 (Box 8:, Folder 72)
    - Ruth Bruzauskas photograph and application, 1940 (Box 8:, Folder 73)
    - Susan Abbe application, photograph, recommendations (5), personal essay, mental health record, admission letter, 1964 (Box 8:, Folder 74)
    - Susan Abbe - student progress reports, 1964-1967 (Box 8:, Folder 75)
    - Susan Abbe - student evaluations of program, 1965-1967 (Box 8:, Folder 76)
    - Susan Abbe - essay, counseling record, bursar records, 1964 (Box 8:, Folder 77)
    - Student enrollment forms, 1965-1972 (Box 8:, Folder 78)
    - Student enrollment lists and inter-office memos, 1961-1968 (Box 8:, Folder 79)
  - Testimonial Dinners
    - Mary B. Heath, 1986 June 3 (Box 8:, Folder 80)
    - Ann M. Lachowicz, 1980 June 9 (Box 8:, Folder 81)
    - Christine McLeod, 1974 December 12 (Box 8:, Folder 82)
    - Hazel A. Eaton, 1973 June 27 (Box 8:, Folder 83)
    - Ona M. Wilcox, 1970 August 9 (Box 8:, Folder 84)
  - Student Organization & Student Council
    [Student Organization materials unless otherwise noted]
    - Regulations- proposed changes, undated (Box 9:, Folder 85)
    - Installation ceremony, 1957 (Box 9:, Folder 86)
    - Student Council minutes, 1965-1971 (Box 9:, Folder 87)
    - Installation ceremony, 1965 May (Box 9:, Folder 88)
    - Minutes, 1966 January - May (Box 9:, Folder 89)
    - Minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 9:, Folder 90)
    - Minutes, 1967-1968 (Box 9:, Folder 91)
    - List of officers, 1968-1969 (Box 9:, Folder 92)
    - Minutes, 1986-1969 (Box 9:, Folder 93)
    - Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 9:, Folder 94)
    - Minutes, 1970-1971 (Box 9:, Folder 95)
    - Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 9:, Folder 96)
    - Minutes, 1972-1976 (Box 9:, Folder 97)
    - Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 9:, Folder 98)
    - Minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 9:, Folder 99)
    - Minutes, 1974-1975 (Box 9:, Folder 100)
    - Minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 9:, Folder 101)
    - Student Council minutes, 1976-1981 (Box 9:, Folder 102)
    - Minutes and Bill of Rights, 1976-1977 (Box 9:, Folder 103)
    - Minutes, 1977-1978 (Box 9:, Folder 104)
    - Minutes, 1978-1979 (Box 9:, Folder 105)
    - Senior / Junior / Freshman class meeting minutes, 1978-1981 (Box 9:, Folder 106)
    - Minutes, 1979-1980 (Box 9:, Folder 107)
    - Minutes and regulations, 1980-1981 (Box 9:, Folder 108)
    - Student Council / Org. and Class meeting minutes, 1981-1982 (Box 9:, Folder 109)
    - Student Council / Org. and Class meeting minutes, 1982-1983 (Box 9:, Folder 110)
    - Student Council / Org. and Class meeting minutes, 1983-1984 (Box 9:, Folder 111)
    - Student Council / Org. and Class meeting minutes, 1984-1985 (Box 9:, Folder 112)
    - Student Council / Org. and Class meeting minutes, 1985-1986 (Box 9:, Folder 113)
    - Student Council / Org. and Class meeting minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 9:, Folder 114)
    - Student Council / Org. and Class meeting minutes, 1987-1988 (Box 9:, Folder 115)
    - Student Council / Org. and Class meeting minutes, 1988-1989 (Box 9:, Folder 116)
    - Student Council / Org. and Class meeting minutes, 1989-1990 (Box 9:, Folder 117)
    - Fundraising and Regulations, circa 1988 (Box 9:, Folder 118)
    - Student Class Officers (listed by year), 1990-1997 (Box 9:, Folder 119)
    - By-Laws and Constitution, 1951-1974 (Box 10:, Folder 120)
    - Student Activities
      - Student Activity fund—procedure and purpose, undated (Box 10:, Folder 121)
      - Play “PAGEANT” -script, undated (Box 10:, Folder 122)
      - Play- “The Shepherd of Judaea”, c.1949 (Box 10:, Folder 123)
      - Christmas pageant, circa 1950 (Box 10:, Folder 124)
      - Student pledge “Nightingale Pledge”, undated (Box 10:, Folder 125)
      - Student Activities, 1954-1967 (Box 10:, Folder 126)
      - Student Activities, 1968-1997 (Box 10:, Folder 127)
      - Class Night / Day Correspondence, memoranda and programs, 1988-1991 (Box 10:, Folder 128)
      - Glee Club, 1930s (Box 10:, Folder 129)
      - Glee Club, 1945-1947 (Box 10:, Folder 130)
      - District Nurse Association, Student affiliation program, 1940-1950 (Box 10:, Folder 131)
      - Student Assistance program, circa 1990 (Box 10:, Folder 132)
      - National Student Nurses Association—amendments to Constitution, 1956 May (Box 10:, Folder 133)
      - Pinning Programs, invitations and tickets, 1993-1997 (Box 10:, Folder 134)
      - Capping ceremonies, 1972-1992 (Box 10:, Folder 135)
      - Commencement speech, 1964 June 11 (Box 10:, Folder 136)
      - Commencement programs, invitations and tickets, 1910-1929 (Box 10:, Folder 137)
      - Commencement programs, invitations and tickets, 1930-1949 (Box 10:, Folder 138)
      - Commencement programs, invitations and tickets, 1972-1979 (Box 10:, Folder 139)
      - Commencement programs, invites, tickets and corresp., 1980-1997 (Box 10:, Folder 140)
      - Alumni Award criteria, by-laws, undated, 1922 (Box 10:, Folder 141)
      - Nurses Regulations, undated (Box 12:, Folder 142)
      - Student Personnel Policies, 1949-1953 (Box 12:, Folder 143)
      - Residence Regulations, 1944-1947 (Box 12:, Folder 144)
      - Student Welfare manual, 1947-1956 (Box 12:, Folder 145)
      - Freshman Student manual and supplement, 1956-1958 (Box 12:, Folder 146)
      - Student Bill of Rights and Responsibilities, 1978 (Box 12:, Folder 147)
      - Dress Code and Grievance procedure, undated
      - Student Affairs manual, part I, circa 1993 (Box 12:, Folder 148)
      - Student Affairs manual, part II, circa 1993 (Box 12:, Folder 149)
      - Procedural manual- student activities, 1980s (Box 12:, Folder 150)
  - Student Manuals
    - For the following dates: (Box 13)
      - (2) 1915, (3) undated, (2) 1941, undated, 1957, 1957-1958 1958-1959, 1959-1960, 1960-1961, 1961-1962, 1962-1963, 1963-1964, 1964-1965, 1965-1966, 1966-1967, 1967-1968, 1968-1969, 1969-1970, 1970-1971
      - 1971-1972, 1972-1973, 1973-1974, 1974-1975, 1975-1976, 1976-1977, 1977-1978, 1979-1980, 1980-1981, 1981-1982, 1984-1985, 1985-1986, 1986-1987, 1987-1988, 1988-1989, 1989-1990, 1990-1991, 1992-1993, 1993-1994, 1994-1995, 1995-1996, 1996-1997 (Box 14)
  - Student Catalogs (with inserts)
    - For the following dates: (Box 15)
      - 1927-1928, (3) undated, 1933-1934, 1933-1934, 1935-1936, 1937-1938, 1940-1941, 1942-1943, 1944-1945, 1946-1947, 1948-1949, 1951-1953, 1953-1955, 1955-1956, 1956-1957, 1957-1958, 1958-1959, 1959-1960, 1960-1961, 1961-1962, 1963-1964, 1964-1965, 1965-1966, 1967-1969, 1968, 1969-1970, 1970-1971, 1971-1972
      - 1972-1973, 1973-1974, 1974-1975, 1975-1976, 1976-1977, 1977-1978, 1978-1979, 1979-1980, 1980-1982, 1981-1983, 1982-1983, 1983-1984, 1984-1985, 1985-1986, 1986-1987, 1987-1988, 1988-1989, 1989-1990, 1990-1991, 1991-1992, 1992-1993, 1993-1994, 1994-1995, 1995-1996 (Box 16)
  - Yearbooks / Unbound class books
    - For the years:
      - 1946, 1947, 1948 (Box 17:, Folder 151)
      - 1951 (2), 1952 (Box 17:, Folder 152)
      - 1963, 1964, 1965, 1966, 1967, 1968, 1969 (Box 17:, Folder 153)
      - 1970, 1971, 1972, 1973 (2 yearbooks & unbound “book”) (Box 17:, Folder 154)
      - 1975, 1978, 1979 (will and 2 yearbooks) (Box 18:, Folder 155)
      - 1981, 1985, 1988 (Box 18:, Folder 156)
      - 1991 (evening division) (Box 18:, Folder 157)
  - Faculty/ Procedural Manuals
    - Procedural manual (revised & alphabetized) parts A - C, 1978 (Box 19:, Folder 158)
    - Parts D - H, 1978 (Box 19:, Folder 159)
    - Parts I - L, 1978 (Box 19:, Folder 160)
    - Parts M - O, 1978 (Box 19:, Folder 161)
    - Parts P - Q, 1978 (Box 19:, Folder 162)
    - Parts R - V, 1978 (Box 19:, Folder 163)
    - Procedural manual Parts A - B, 1987 January (Box 19:, Folder 164)
    - Parts C - F, 1987 January (Box 19:, Folder 165)
    - Parts G - D, 1987 January (Box 19:, Folder 166)
    - Parts P - V, 1987 January (Box 19:, Folder 167)
    - Faculty Directory, 1969-1970 (Box 20:, Folder 168)
    - Rules, Charters and By-Laws of Hospital, 1924-1925 (Box 20:, Folder 169)
    - Middlesex Hospital Flyers and Reports, 1917-1947 (Box 20:, Folder 170)
    - Inter-office memoranda, 1979-1981 (Box 20:, Folder 171)
    - Inter-office memoranda re:change in evening residence dir., 1983 (Box 20:, Folder 172)
    - Faculty manual Part I (revised), 1988 May (Box 20:, Folder 173)
    - Faculty manual Part II (revised), 1988 May (Box 20:, Folder 174)
    - Faculty manual additions (revised), 1987-1988 (Box 20:, Folder 175)
    - Faculty manual Parts I - II, circa 1993 (Box 20:, Folder 176)
    - Faculty Manual Parts III - IV, circa 1993 (Box 20:, Folder 177)
    - Faculty Manual Parts V - VI, circa 1993 (Box 20:, Folder 178)
  - Curriculum